享受这一刻吧 梅尔·米达尔达
Drink the moment, Mel Medarda.
第一次的感受是最特别的
There is no time like your first.
我是你们的一员
I'm one of you?
是法师
A mage?
我们所能施展法术的方式各有不同
We each have our own expressions.
你的尤为罕见
Yours is quite rare.
是一种潜移默化的心灵之术
An empath. Attuned to the ethereal.
可以感知他人的潜意识 并反射他人的法术
Able to sense others' inner selves and bend their magic.
既是媒介 也是镜子
A conduit and a mirror.
那么你又是什么
What does that make you?
始终藏在幻术之后 不肯以真面目示人
Even now you hide your true face behind illusions.
真相不过是一种极致的幻术
Truth is the greatest illusion of them all.
依我看 面具背后是你的恐惧
I think beneath that mask you're scared.
我能识破你的花招 这对你构成了威胁
I can see through your tricks. That makes me a threat.
天赋异禀之人往往会受制于自负
For the gifted, arrogance is the ultimate threat.
你的能力固然珍贵
Your power has merit.
但想要取你性命
But should one want you dead,
也只需一把利刃而已
a simple blade would do nicely.
我哥哥他在哪儿
Where is my brother?
真的很遗憾 在他的事上 你母亲没有说谎
Regrettably, his fate wasn't among your mother's lies.
你杀了他
You killed him.
我给过安蓓萨无数次 为僭越行为赎罪的机会
I gave Ambessa every opportunity to atone for her transgressions.
可她选择了自傲 而非子嗣
She chose pride over progeny.
但你不必背负她的罪责
But you need not bear her crimes.
这场考验 这整个的迷局
The test. This whole charade.
一切只为让我加入你们
You want to recruit me.
你的能力在快速成长
Your talents developed quickly.
这并不是巧合 是奥术正在觉醒
It's no coincidence. The Arcane is waking up.
我母亲到底干了什么
What has my mother done?
一场浩劫在所难免
A calamity is approaching,
规模堪比曾经的符文战争
rivaling even the ancient Rune Wars.
安蓓萨是此事的主导
Ambessa sits at the helm,
她对权力已经迷恋到无法自拔
blinded by her thirst for legacy.
我们试图改变她 但都无济于事
Our efforts to divert her course have foundered.
我们承受不起再一次失败了
We can't afford another failure.
所以你才看中了我 拿我当致命一击
This is what you see in me? A silver bullet?
你能带来救赎
I see salvation of your city,
拯救你的城邦 以及数以万计的生灵
countless others beyond.
她是我的母亲
She's my mother.
即便犯下种种错误
For all her faults,
那也是因为她想尽力维护我们的家族
she has always done what she thought was best for the family.
当初你哥哥也这么认为
Your brother thought so too,
直到他发现了她的秘密
until he uncovered her secret.
你的降生
Your birth,
和你整个人生从来都不是一场意外
the entire course of your life, was no accident.
她将你隐姓埋名 只因你是她求之不得的
She hid you because you are that which she covets most:
利器
a weapon.
如今 你因为加入我们而得到重生
Today you've been born into a new family,
很快你会意识到 曾经的家再也回不去了
from which you'll find there is sadly no return.
那些从未接触过奥术的人害怕我们
Those untouched by the Arcane fear us.
这是什么
What is this?
见面礼 愿你未来顺遂
A welcome to your future.
独行的法师将要面对的世界凶险万分
The world is a perilous place for a solitary mage...
姐妹
sister.
《英雄联盟:双城之战》
第二季第八集
本WEB版外挂字幕由  风吹来的那片云  双语合并
很抱歉 没能救活他
I regret that I couldn't save him.
他的伤势实在太重了
His injuries were too severe.
我们不会为死去的战士哀悼
We do not lament a warrior's death.
我们只会为他复仇
We avenge it.
他们的先驱怎么样了
What of their Herald?
血清能帮助维克托再维持一段时间
The blood should sustain Viktor for a short while.
接下来就全凭他自己了
Beyond that, it is up to his own will.
你曾承诺能使人起死回生
You promised a cure to death.
那取决于维克托是否能挺过来
An outcome dependent on Viktor's survival.
博士
Doctor.
你的才干应当受到嘉奖
Your ingenuity deserves praise.
维克托
Viktor.
我心怀感激
I am... grateful.
我眼中的世界如今变得
The world I now see is more...
更加的通透了
lucid than ever.
你的意识能进入你的追随者
You can inhabit your followers?
我们是一体的
We are one.
这个叫作光荣进化
This is the Glorious Evolution.
本来可以这样的
Or it could have been.
但我知道我时日不多了
I sense my twilight approaching.
在海克斯飞门底部 有一个异常点正在恶变
An anomaly festers beneath the Hexgates.
我相信它能够帮助博士实现起死回生
I believe it has the capacity to complete the doctor's transformation.
那它能帮你实现为他人进化吗
This will allow you to evolve others?
理论上能
In theory.
但杰斯的攻击收效显著
But Jayce's attack has done its work.
现在的我
I do
面对他们可能的防守 已经有些无力招架了
not have the strength to overcome the defense he will raise against me.
我派人护送你去异常点
I will deliver you to this anomaly,
但你要先为我的这些士兵 实现一次强化
if you agree to empower every soldier I bring you.
我将为所有有此意愿的人实现进化
I will evolve all those willing.
蔚
Vi?
快点 得赶紧离开这里
Come on. We need to get out of here.
不 伊莎
No! Isha!
瞧瞧你
Shh. Easy there.
找了三个大夫才救回你的小命
Took all the three docs to patch you up.
洛里斯
Loris?
不知道你能不能扛过来
Wasn't sure you'd pull through.
得亏你脑袋够硬
Thank that thick noggin of yours.
其他人在哪儿
Where are the others?
凯特琳呢 金克丝呢
Cait? Jinx?
金克丝她...
Jinx.
凯特琳本想陪在这儿亲自告诉你
Caitlyn wanted to be here to tell you herself.
洛里斯
Loris.
你就说吧
Spit it out.
或许我们还是有得谈的
Maybe we can negotiate.
和安蓓萨没得谈
Not with Ambessa.
她的眼神已经告诉我
I saw it in her eyes.
她要让整个皮尔特沃夫 为我的背叛付出代价
She will burn Piltover to the ground for my betrayal.
你不用过分自责
You can't blame yourself.
我不需要你的安慰
I don't need consolation.
我需要应对计划
I need a plan.
抓起来了
Arrested?
这边我能处理 麦迪
I can handle this, Maddie.
你去看看我父亲吧
Check on my father?
蔚
Vi.
她救了你的命
She saved your life.
你能不能先冷静一下听我说
If you will calm down for one...
即便她明知道你不会对她手下留情
Knowing you'd never have done the same for her.
你怎么知道我不会
We'll never know, will we?
你根本就没给我机会 参与你那部分的计划
You didn't let me in on that part of your plan.
幸亏没让你参与
Clearly the right call,
你从来就没有信任过她 没准儿还想把她给塞进棺材里
since you still can't trust her enough not to shove her in a box.
信任
Trust?
你当我是个傻瓜吗 她出手救我就是个巧合
You believe I'm so daft I can't recognize a contingency?
她在那儿不是为了保护我
She wasn't there for my benefit.
而是为了盯着我 因为你不信我会按照你的计划行事
You didn't trust me to follow through.
这能怪我吗
Can you blame me?
是谁不声不响地搭上了 那个自私狡猾的战争狂
How long were you sidled up with that shifty, self-serving war pig?
她给你灌了什么迷魂汤 你对她那么言听计从
She oinked poison in your ear. You just ate it.
我心里有数
I know.
金克丝当时唯一的要求 就是把你带到安全的地方
The only thing Jinx cared about was getting you to safety.
然后她就投降了
Then she just surrendered.
我还没来得及想对策 她就被那些人拖走了
I didn't even have time to think before they hauled her off.
她现在被关在地牢里 我还...
She's being held in the bunker while
我还没想好怎么办
I decide what to do.
我想先等你醒过来
I was waiting for you to recover.
凯特琳 她和以前不一样了
Cait, she's changed.
没人能抹去曾经犯下的错 谁也不能
We can't erase our mistakes. None of us.
谁规定我们不能有再来一次的机会
Who decides who gets a second chance?
如果你是来杀我的 麻烦利索点儿
If you're here to kill me, make sure to finish the job.
蔚觉得你和以前不一样了
Vi thinks you've changed.
她就是个死脑筋 咱俩都清楚
She can't accept what you and I know.
根本不会有什么大团圆结局
There are no happy endings.
不想再为自己说点什么吗
Is that all you have to say for yourself?
不会有审判的
There won't be a trial.
但我想给你一次机会 听听你对曾经犯下的罪过
I'm giving you this one chance to account for your actions,
和造成的伤痛做何解释
all the pain you've caused.
做再多善事也无法洗清曾经犯下的罪
No amount of good deeds can undo our crimes.
你要干什么就快动手吧
Do what you came here to do.
恨你的同时
Hating you...
我也在恨我自己
I've hated myself.
我已经快要撑不下去了
I just don't have the energy for it any longer.
我不知道你妈妈当时也在那里
I didn't know your mom was there.
虽然这也并不能改变什么 但我那时
It probably wouldn't have made a difference, but...
的确不知道
I didn't know.
杰斯
Jayce?
你这是怎么了
What happened to you?
我不要紧的
Doesn't matter.
我也遇到了些事情
Something happened to me too.
那次袭击你我幸免于难 全是因为你
You're the reason we didn't die in the attack.
看来的确如此
Apparently so.
这事你知道多久了
How long have you known?
从那天开始 我就有种说不清楚的感觉
It started then. Feelings I couldn't explain.
但这个
But this...
至今我也无法完全理解
I still don't fully understand.
为什么只救我 为什么不救其他人
Why just me? Why not save all of them?
那不是我能决定的
It wasn't a decision.
前一秒你还在议会上发言
One moment you're addressing the Council,
下一秒我们就站在废墟里了
the next we're standing in rubble.
我完全不知道我自己做过些什么
I didn't have any greater awareness.
我怎么知道你到底有没有在撒谎呢
How can I know you aren't lying to me?
你为什么会觉得我在撒谎
Why would you think I am?
因为你利用了我 还有维克托 为了海克斯科技
Because you used me, and Viktor, for Hextech.
你把我们两个当成是投资
You called us "investments."
两个绝顶聪明的青年发明家
Two brilliant young inventors who shared a penchant
都致力于创造奇迹
for impossible surprises.
将魔法从神秘的传说变成现实的应用
Carrying magic from myth to machine.
承载着希望 鼓舞了人心
Rallying the hope and hearts of a nation.
你俩确实是一种明智的投资
You were a wise investment.
请给你我一点和平相处的时间 杰斯
Allow us a moment of civility, Jayce.
我们必须谈谈
We must talk.
维克托
Viktor.
你是怎么进到这儿的
How did you get in here?
你当年能站在这里 我也是有贡献的
You once benefitted from my knowledge of this place.
那是很久以前的事了
That was a long time ago.
如果你愿意给我机会
Had you given me the chance,
我就能向你展示我的成就
I would have shown you the merits of my work.
我们的成就
Our work.
不 是你自己执迷不悟
No, this is your obsession.
你对那些人所做的一切 都是你的一意孤行
Everything you've done to these people, you did alone.
或许吧
Perhaps.
但我不再是孤身一人
But I'm alone no longer.
现在他们每个人都时刻与我同在
I now speak with all their voices.
有什么话你就直说吧
Say what you came here to say.
我觉得吧 你其实已经明白
Somehow I think you already understand
该怎么做才能完成我的使命
what must transpire to complete my mission.
我希望通过和平的方式实现
I would prefer to do so in peace.
但诺克萨斯人有别的想法
The Noxian has other intentions.
我母亲
Mother?
奥术在你体内涌动
The Arcane stirs within you.
维克托 为了大家好 请你离海克斯飞门远点
Viktor, for all our sakes, stay away from the Hexgates.
你变得固守陈规了 杰斯
Your mind has become rigid, Jayce.
恐惧影响了你的判断
Fear clouds your judgment.
这一连串事件因你而起
This chain of events started with you.
我苦思冥想 却怎么也想不通
In my confusion, I was unable to reconcile this.
但现在我终于明白
But I now understand.
一切终将会走向光荣进化
The Glorious Evolution is destined.
让我们就像过去那样再做一次搭档吧
Let us instead do this once again as partners.
我的搭档已经死在这里了
My partner died in this room.
我曾尽我所能去避免如今的局面
It was my sincere desire to avoid this.
博士
Doctor.
你现在可以开始了
You may begin the process.
走开
Go away.
你来得太迟了
You're too late.
这地方真够可以的
Oh, it's a hell of a place.
倒是能说明马可斯的为人
It says something about the late Marcus
他居然说把你姐姐关起来比杀了她...
that he found imprisoning your sister to be a greater mercy
更加仁慈
than killing her.
杀人可不仁慈
Killing isn't mercy.
看来这副皮囊下的 叛逆之火还没有熄灭呀
A spark of rebellion still burns inside that husk, I see.
没错 杀人偿命 循环往复
No. Killing is a cycle.
远在范德尔和我之前就有了
One that started long before Vander and me.
你们俩之后也不会停止
And it will continue long after the two of you.
可我已经受够原地打转了
I'm done running in circles.
我们为自己画地成牢
We build our own prisons.
用誓言 规则和承诺铸成围栏
Bars forged of oaths, codes, commitments.
用自我怀疑与认知局限建起高墙
Walls of self-doubt and accepted limitation.
我们困在这些自我设限的身份牢笼中
We inhabit these cells, these identities,
还美其名曰“这就是我”
and call them "us."
我曾经以为干掉那些所谓的 狱卒便可以挣脱牢笼
I thought I could break free by eliminating those I deemed my jailors.
但是
But...
金克丝
Jinx...
只有下定决心 放下离开 才能终结循环
I think the cycle only ends when you find the will to walk away.
金克丝
Jinx?
你来干什么
What are you doing?
我从守卫那里顺来了钥匙
I swiped these from the guard station.
如果你肯帮我们
If you come, help,
把你那一身发明炸弹的本事 用来做好事
use all that explosive potential of yours for good,
说不定你的人生就能被改写
maybe we could rewrite your story,
就像你为底城做的 你觉得呢
like you did with Zaun. What do you think?
好啊 蔚
Sure, Vi.
你永远都不会不管我的 对吗
You're never gonna give up on me, are you?
嘿
Hey!
好了 你不必再为我的事烦心了
You don't have to worry about me anymore.
也不必因为过得快乐而感到内疚
You don't need to feel guilty about being happy.
你应该和她一起
You deserve to be with her.
等一下
Wait.
我早就是无可救药了
There's no good version of me.
你想要干什么
What are you gonna do?
终结循环
Break the cycle.
金克丝
Jinx!
对不起
I'm sorry.
之前是我太蠢了
I've been an idiot.
太混蛋了
And an ass.
你也受伤了
You're hurting too.
自从我小时候记事起
For as long as I can recall,
我就一直努力成为 米达尔达家族的典范
I have chased the archetype of a Medarda.
我以为我的使命是让家族发扬光大
I believed it my calling to merit the blood in my veins.
而一切竟全是谎言
It was all a lie.
这血统对我而言是陌生的
This blood is alien to me.
然而它竟然能够主宰我的整个人生
Yet it has dictated the course of my entire life.
原来我只是一个过客
I'm no more than a passenger.
在自艾自怜中度日
A life I spent in self-pity.
现在都结束了 我再也回不去了
Now it's gone. I can never return to it.
我最近被很多事困惑
I've been confused about a lot lately.
但有一件事我深信不疑
But there's one thing I know in my bones.
这世上没有什么力量能控制得了你
There is no force in this world that can control you.
你永远都不会只是个过客
You will never be a passenger.
肃静
Quiet.
恕我失礼 但留给我们的时间不多了
Forgive me. But we don't have much time.
暴风雨即将袭来
A storm is coming,
恐怕是一场皮尔特沃夫
the likes of which Piltover,
乃至整个符文之地都未曾经历过的
perhaps Runeterra itself, has never faced.
这个怪物
This creature
潜入了各位现在所在的这个房间
infiltrated the very room you're standing in.
我们当时险些丧命
And we barely survived.
几百个这样的怪物正朝这儿来
Hundreds more are on the way.
在诺克萨斯将军的率领下
The Noxian general is leading them.
这场战争无关理想 也无关领土
This isn't a fight for ideals or territory.
而是关乎人性的存亡
It's a fight for humanity itself.
我请求 不 我恳求各位
I'm asking... No, begging you, every one of you,
无论你是来自上城还是底城 请与我们并肩作战
Topside and bottom, to aid us in this coming war.
这场战争无法避免
And it will be a war.
这样的要求是有些强人所难 但这是我们唯一的希望
Now, this isn't a fair request, but it is our only hope.
敌人太过强大
The forces against us are too great.
我们必须团结一切可以团结的力量
We need every hand we can get.
把它推倒
Bring them down!
我们不得不放弃城郊 将布防集中到海克斯飞门
We're abandoning the city's outskirts to stage our defense at the Hexgates.
这是能拯救我们的最后堡垒
The final bastion of our salvation.
如果你选择逃难 那就别停下脚步
If you choose to flee, don't stop running.
但我选择战斗
But I'm choosing to fight.
我希望你们能跟我一起
And I pray that you will join me.
赶紧的 跟上 快去
Let's go, let's go, let's go.
就觉得你可能会在这儿
Had a feeling I might find you here.
我真的以为她肯帮忙的
I really believed she'd help.
说吧 说你早就提醒过我
Say it. You told me so.
我就是一个蠢货 居然还会再次相信她
I was an idiot to trust her. I went behind your back.
我背着你放走了她 每次我都选错
I choose wrong every time.
我的一错再错
And because of it,
让所有人都离我而去
I've lost everyone.
你真以为我非得把守卫 都调去海克斯飞门不可吗
You really think I needed all the guards at the Hexgates?
不好意思 我看穿了你的小心思
Sorry to say, you've grown a bit predictable.
听我说
Uh, listen,
你不在的时候 我和别人...
while you were gone, I saw someone...
凯特琳
Cait.
我他妈不在乎
I don't fucking care.
你还活着
You're alive.
我知道黒色玫瑰的事了
I know about the Black Rose.
你看到的只是表面 他们不过是虚假的谎言
You know a facade. They are nothing but lies.
你说过最高明的谎言 都披着真相的外衣
You taught me the best lies come wrapped in truth.
基诺到底出了什么事
What really happened to Kino?
你哥哥是被好奇心害死的
Your brother was struck with curiosity.
他掉进了他们布下的网
He got caught in their web
越是挣扎 就会越难挣脱
and, with every action, grew more deeply entangled.
你就由着他死了
So you let him die?
我怀胎十月生下他
I carried him in my belly,
一口一口奶水养大
nursed him from my bosom.
他是我心中最柔软的部分
He was all the sweetness in my heart.
所以他们才把他夺走
For that, they took him,
给我留下一道永远都无法愈合的伤口
carved into me a wound that will never close.
我真的希望你永远不用受这样的苦
I pray you never suffer the agony
为救一个孩子而不得不舍弃另一个
of being forced to forsake one child to save another.
你应该早点告诉我的
You should have come to me.
已经无可挽回 说了只会让你也难受
You'd have made the impossible intolerable.
我做了你做不到的事
I did what you could not.
为了你 为了家族
For you. For the family.
皮尔特沃尔和你的仇怨毫不相干
Piltover has nothing to do with your feud.
立刻上船 立刻启程离开这儿
Board your boats, leave our shores.
我和你一起走 我们一起为基诺复仇
I will join you. We can avenge Kino together.
这并非简单的复仇 孩子
This is more than vengeance, child.
这些法师在我们头顶悬了一把剑
These mages dangle over our heads a sword
只要飞得过高 就会被刺穿
that impales us should we rise too high.
他们的本性违反了 诺克萨斯核心的原则
Their very nature violates the most core of Noxian principles,
那就是在战场上人人平等
that every one of us is equal on the battlefield.
运用计谋 挥洒汗水 钢铁护身
That through cunning, sweat, and steel...
命运要由自己掌控
we shape our destinies.
你跑来为你朋友们的生死游说
The fact you've come to parley for your friends' lives prove
足以证明你还不具备
you still lack the wrath necessary
打败黑色玫瑰这种劲敌 所需要的雷霆手段
to defeat an enemy like the Rose.
而我找到了其他办法
I've found another way.
试想一下 孩子
Imagine, child,
一支不必再畏惧死亡的军队
an army that need never fear death.
母亲 你做了什么
What have you done, Mother?
博士
Doctor.
你现在可以开始了
You may begin the process.
那好吧
Very well.
看来是时候要说再见了
I guess this is goodbye.
真的非常感谢你 陪伴我度过孤独 杨小姐
Thank you very much for your company in my solitude, Ms. Young.
我会怀念我们曾说过的话
I will miss our talks.
不
No.
你不会的
You won't.
字幕翻译: 付博文 韩一旻